yeah I think that the globalization of
the economy first of all it's very
important that people realize that this
is an economic trajectory it's a very
specific process it's about the
deregulation of global trade and finance
what does it mean to deregulate global
trade and finance it actually means do
regulating the movement and the
activities of large multinational
corporations and banks now most people
today recognize that very large
multinational corporations are
problematic they recognize that very
often they are influencing the political
process in an undue and very in just way
and therefore the link between the power
of multinational corporations and this
deregulation of Trade and finance is an
incredibly important issue I think this
structural problem with deregulating
global trade and Finance is more
important that we understand that and
that we demonize particular corporations
or demonize the people within them this
is not a question of the good guys and
bad guys
it's a question of scale it's a question
of when business entities become larger
than governments we have a structural
problem the for profit motive becomes
unduly important that doesn't mean that
the for profit motive is in and of
itself wrong it doesn't mean that we
can't have business that is truly free
and where there is an enterprise
that is proud of performing well of
providing goods and services for
consumers but it needs to be under the
umbrella of social and ecological
concerns and priorities so for a long
time in AIESEC we've been trying to
raise awareness about this and we've
been trying to show that the process of
reregulate in global trade would be a
relatively simple thing to do
structurally it's not so easy to do
politically until people understand it
better so that there's a larger critical
mass of people demanding this of their
governments but it's beginning to happen
there's already a growing opposition to
the further globalization of the economy
in the meanwhile at the local level
around the world there are many groups
and institutions working to strengthen
local economies and local economies by
definition our economy is where the
communication between producers and
consumers starts to happen where there
is a greater human scale interaction
between the two the distances are
shortened but we're talking about a
process of shortening distances this is
not about absolutes
it's not about saying well you should
only eat local food right now in many
parts of the world if we said to people
you have to eat only local you'd be
saying you're going to live on cotton
and nothing else you're going to live on
on canola oil and nothing else so we
have to understand that we're talking
about a process of change of moving
towards the
defying economic activities around